ebaycommercenetwork.com 2017-05-04

# eBay Product Ads – Advertise your products to eBay shoppers - Privacy Policy

### Your Privacy Rights

This Privacy Policy ("Policy") describes your privacy rights regarding our collection, use, storage, sharing, and protection of your personal information. It governs your participation on the eBayCommerce.com, Shopping.com, Epinions.com, DealTime.com, and PriceTool.com websites (including the versions of these sites in foreign jurisdictions), their sister sites, and all co-branded versions of these sites or any successor brand that eBay may designate from time to time inits discretion (in the United States or foreign jurisdictions), which are referred to collectively as the "eBay Commerce Network" or "ECN," along with their related sites, applications, services, and tools, regardless of how you access or use them, including through mobile devices. 

You accept this Privacy Policy when you sign up for, access, or use our products, services, content, features, technologies, or functions offered on our websites and all related sites, applications, and services (collectively "eBay Commerce Network Services"). 

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the amended terms on this site. Any such amendment shall take effect when such amendment is sent by email or posted on the eBay Commerce Network. Throughout this Privacy Policy, we use the term "personal information" to describe information that can be associated with a specific person and could be used to identify that person. We do not consider personal information to include information that has been made anonymous or aggregated so that it can no longer be used, whether in combination with other information or otherwise, to identify a specific person. 

### Contents & Summary

A table summarizing the contents of this Policy appears below, followed by the Policy in full. Should there be any discrepancy between the table and the full Policy, the language of the full Policy shall govern. 

Scope and Consent

| 

By using the eBay Commerce Network, and its related sites, applications, services and tools, and/or registering for an account, you expressly consent to our collection, use, disclosure, and retention of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy and in our User Agreement.   
  
---|---  
  
Global Privacy Standards

| 

eBay Inc. has established a set of Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs), which are our global privacy standards for all eBay Inc. companies. They are a commitment by eBay Inc. to protect your personal information and honor our privacy obligations regardless of where your personal information is collected, processed, or stored.  
  
Mobile Privacy

| 

If we offer the ability for you to use our services and tools using a mobile device, the provisions of this Privacy Policy apply to all such mobile access and use.   
  
Children’s Privacy

| 

The sites and services provided by eBay Inc. are not intended for children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from users in this age group.   
  
Collection of Personal Information

| 

We collect the different types of personal information in order to provide you with the use of and access to our sites, applications, services, and tools, and to help us personalize and improve your experience. This includes information we collect automatically (such as device ID, device type, geo-location information, computer and connection information, statistics on page views, traffic to and from the sites, referral URL, ad data, IP address, standard web log information, and anonymous information collected through our use cookies and web beacons) and information you give us (such as information you enter on our sites or you provide to us in context of using our sites, applications, services, or tools). Occasionally, we may also receive or collect supplemental information about you from third parties. This may include, but is not limited to, demographic information, navigation information, additional contact information, credit check information, and additional information about you from credit bureaus or other sources, as permitted by law.   
  
Social Media

| 

By associating an account managed by a third party with your eBay account and authorizing eBay to have access to this information, you agree that eBay may collect, use, and store information from these websites in accordance with this Privacy Policy.   
  
Communication Preferences and Marketing

| 

We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent. We may combine your information with information we collect from other companies and use it to improve and personalize our services, content, and advertising. You can control how and when you want to receive notifications from the ECN from the account settings section within your account.   
  
Use and Disclosure

| 

We may share your personal information with the eBay family of companies or others as further described in the full Policy.   
  
Information you share on the site

| 

Ratings, reviews, tags, comments, and other content you contribute may be displayed publicly on the eBay Commerce Network and elsewhere on the web, sometimes alongside your member or user name. Reviews submitted through our product review services cannot later be deleted. For some of our features, other members may be able to request email notifications of your new public content or publish their own comments to your reviews. We may use the public content to develop aggregate ratings, personalize site views, market products or identify or feature popular members. Your wish lists are public by default.   
  
Cookies

| 

We use Cookies to recognize you as a customer; customize ECN Services, content, and advertising; measure promotional effectiveness; help ensure that your account security is not compromised; mitigate risk and prevent fraud; and to promote trust and safety across our sites and services. For more detailed information on our use of Cookies, see [Cookies and Your Privacy](http://pages.ebay.com/help/account/cookies-web-beacons.html "Cookies and Your Privacy").   
  
Access, review, and modification

| 

You can review and edit your personal information at any time by logging in to your account and reviewing your account settings and profile. You can close your account at any time by contacting Customer Support in the [United States](http://www.shopping.com/sc/contact-us "United States"), in the [United Kingdom](http://uk.shopping.com/sc/contact-us "United Kingdom"), in [France](http://fr.shopping.com/sc/contact-us "France"), in [Germany](http://de.shopping.com/sc/contact-us "Germany") or in [Australia](http://au.shopping.com/sc/contact-us "Australia") (for Shopping.com) or [clicking here](http://www.epinions.com/help/feedback_general.html "clicking here") (for Epinions.com).   
  
Protection and Retention

| 

We store and process your personal information on our computers in the US and elsewhere in the world, where we protect your information using physical, technical, and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, or alteration. We retain information as long as it is necessary and relevant for our operations.   
  
Third Parties

| 

Our ECN websites may contain links to other third party websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these sites. If you have concerns about how other websites collect and use information about you, make sure to read that site's privacy policy.   
  
Contact Us

| 

You may write to us at: eBay Inc. Attn: Legal - Global Privacy Practices, 2145 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, California 95125, or by using the [Contact Us form](http://ocsnext.ebay.com/ocs/cusr?domain=Help&query=Privacy%20policy&from=1003146 "Contact Us form"). More information about the Global Privacy Office and how to contact us is available at our [eBay Privacy Center](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/about-us "eBay Privacy Center").   
  
### Scope and Consent

When you use any of the eBay Commerce Network websites listed above, you are contracting with eBay Inc., with offices located at 2145 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, CA 95125. If you reside outside of the United States, eBay Inc. is your data controller.

By using the ECN websites or their related applications, services, and tools, or by registering for an account with any of our websites, you expressly consent to our collection, use, disclosure, and retention of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy and in the eBay Commerce Network User Agreement, as well as to the transfer and storage of your personal information to our servers in the United States and elsewhere in the world where we have facilities.

### Global Privacy Standards

In addition to the privacy practices set out in this Privacy Policy, eBay Inc. has established a set of Corporate Rules (also referred to as "Binding Corporate Rules" or "BCRs"), which are our global privacy standards for all eBay Inc. companies. 

These BCRs have been approved by a number of European Union privacy regulators. They are a commitment by eBay Inc. to protect your personal information and honor our privacy obligations regardless of where your personal information is collected, processed, or stored. Depending on where you reside, the BCRs may also provide you some additional privacy rights through your local privacy regulator or court.

For more information about our BCRs and our global privacy practices and principles, including information on how to contact us with any questions, visit our [eBay Privacy Center](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/privacy "eBay Privacy Center").

### Mobile Privacy

We may offer you the ability for you to connect with the ECN websites, or use our applications, services, and tools using a mobile device, either through a mobile application or via a mobile-optimized website. The provisions of this Privacy Policy apply to all such mobile access and use of mobile devices. This Privacy Policy will be referenced by all such mobile applications or mobile-optimized websites.

### Children's Privacy

The eBay Commerce Network websites are all general audience websites, and neither they nor any of their related sites, applications, services, or tools are intended for children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information via our websites, applications, services, or tools from users in this age group.

### Collection of Personal Information

You can browse our ECN websites without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. Personal information is only associated to your account when you sign in as a registered user. If you register for an account with us, you choose to give us your personal information and are not anonymous to us. If you choose to provide us with personal information, you consent to the transfer and storage of that information on our servers located in the United States and around the world.

We collect the following types of personal information in order to provide you with the use of and access to our sites, applications, services, and tools, and to help us personalize and improve your experience: 

**Information we collect automatically:** When you visit our sites, use our applications, services, and tools, or interact with our advertising or content, we automatically collect information sent to us by your computer, mobile device, or other access device. This information is associated with you personally only when you sign in as a registered user, and includes but is not limited to:

  * device ID or unique identifier, device type, geo-location information, computer and connection information, statistics on page views, traffic to and from the sites, referral URL, ad data, IP address and standard web log information; and
  * anonymous information collected through our use cookies and web beacons.

**Information you give us:** We collect and store any information you enter on our sites or you provide to us in context of using our sites, applications, services, or tools. This may include, but is not limited to:

  * information you provide us when registering for an account, including email address, phone number, mobile telephone number, physical contact information, and (depending on the service used) sometimes financial information, such as credit card or bank account numbers;
  * addition information you may provide to us via social media sites or services
  * transactional information based on your activities on the sites (such as bidding, buying, selling, item and content you generate or that relates to your account);
  * shipping, billing and other information you provide to purchase or ship an item;
  * information provided in the context of community discussions, chats, dispute resolution, correspondence through our sites, or correspondence sent to us
  * additional personal information we ask you to submit to authenticate yourself or if we believe you are violating site policies (for example, we may ask you to send us an ID or bill to verify your address, or to answer additional questions online to help verify your identity or ownership of an item you list)

**Mobile:** When you download or use our Mobile Applications, or access one of our mobile optimized sites, we may receive information about your location and your mobile device, including a unique identifier for your device. We may use this information to provide you with location-based services, such as advertising, search results, and other personalized content. Most mobile devices allow you to control or disable location services in the device’s settings menu. If you have questions about how to disable your device’s location services, we recommend you contact your mobile service carrier or the manufacture of your particular device.

**Information from other sources** : We may receive or collect supplemental information about you from third party sources and add it to our account information. This may include, but is not limited to, demographic information, navigation information, additional contact information, credit check information, and additional information about you from credit bureaus or other sources, as permitted by law.

### Social Media

We may offer sign-on services that allow you to use third party login credentials to access the ECN websites or related applications, services or tools. We also may offer services that allow you to share information with third party social media websites such as Facebook, Google Plus, Twitter, and others.

You may choose to provide us with access to certain personal information stored by such third party websites. The personal information we have access to varies by website and is controlled by your privacy settings on that website and by your consent. By associating an account managed by a third party with your ECN account and authorizing eBay to have access to this information, you agree that eBay may collect, use, and store information from these websites in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Communication Preferences and Marketing (Opt-out)

We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent. We may combine your information with information we collect from other companies and use it to improve and personalize our services, content and advertising.

If you do not wish to receive marketing communications from us, you can indicate your communications preference in [My eBay](http://pages.ebay.com/help/account/my-ebay.html "My eBay"), or within the direct communication from us. If do not wish to participate in our ad-customization programs, you can opt-out by following the directions provided within the applicable advertisement, or directly at our [Ad Choice program](http://pages.ebay.com/help/account/adchoice.html "Ad Choice program").

You can opt-out of receiving marketing communications (including customized ads) from the eBay Commerce Network at any time, but you may not opt-out of administrative emails (for example, emails about your transactions or policy changes) while you are a member of the eBay Commerce Network.

### Use and Disclosure

Our primary purpose in collecting personal information is to provide you with secure and smooth access to the ECN websites and/or use of our services, applications, and tools, to provide you with requested customer service and relevant information about your account and our services, and to provide you with a safe, efficient, and customized experience. You agree that we may use your personal information to:

  * operate our websites and provide access to our applications, services, and tools;
  * provide customer support;
  * analyze site and user behavior and prepare aggregated reports; 
  * prevent, detect, and investigate fraud, security breaches, and potentially prohibited or illegal activities, and enforce our User Agreement;
  * measure and improve our sites and services, and customize our services, content, and advertising;
  * contact you, either via email or telephone, to resolve disputes, collect fees, troubleshoot problems with your account or our sites, services, applications, or tools, or to deliver targeted marketing, service updates, or promotional offers in accordance with your stated communication preferences; or
  * provide other services requested by you, as described at the time when we collect the information from you, or to contact you for other purposes authorized by law.

We may disclose personal information to respond to legal requirements, enforce our policies, respond to claims that a listing or other content violates the rights of others, or protect anyone's rights, property, or safety. Such information will be disclosed in accordance with this Privacy Policy and applicable laws and regulations. As stated above, we do not disclose your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent.

We may also share your personal information with:

  * [Members of the eBay Inc. corporate family](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/about-us/corporate-family "Members of the eBay Inc. corporate family") to provide joint content and services (like registration, transactions, and customer support), to help detect and prevent potentially illegal acts, violations of our policies, fraud and/or data security breaches, and to guide decisions about their products, sites, applications, services and tools, and communications. Members of our corporate family will use this information to send you marketing communications only if you have requested their services and will use your personal information in compliance with their Privacy Policy and our global privacy standards.
  * Service providers under contract who help with our business operations (such as, but not limited to, fraud investigations, bill collection, affiliate and rewards programs, site operations, and co-branded credit cards).
  * Other third parties to whom you explicitly ask us to send your information (or about whom you are otherwise explicitly notified and consent to when using a specific service). On the eBay Commerce Network, you may have opportunities to express interest in or register for third-party products and services. If you do, we will provide information about you to the third party to implement your request;
  * Law enforcement, governmental agencies, or authorized third parties, in response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity or any other activity that may expose us, you, or any other eBay Commerce Network user to legal liability. In such events, we will only disclose information relevant and necessary to the investigation or inquiry, such as name, city, state, ZIP code, telephone number, email address, User ID history, IP address, fraud complaints, and anything else we may deem relevant to the investigation;
  * Credit bureaus with which we may report information about your account, including information on late payments, missed payments, or other defaults on your account may be reflected in your credit report;
  * Other business entities, should we plan to merge with or be acquired by that business entity. (Should such a combination occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information. If your personal information would be used contrary to this policy, you will receive prior notice); and/or
  * For our internal development and market research, we may collect survey information from you and share the results with our affiliates, consultants, vendors and service providers as applicable and authorized by this Privacy Policy.

Without limiting the above, in an effort to respect your privacy and our ability to keep the community free from bad actors, we will disclose your personal information to law enforcement, other government officials, or other third parties only if such parties have a subpoena, court order, or substantially similar legal procedure, or if we believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss or to report suspected illegal activity.

### Information You Share on Site

Some portions of the eBay Commerce Network allow you to contribute ratings, reviews, tags, comments, and other content, either on one of our websites or via our product review services on other websites. This content may be displayed publicly on the eBay Commerce Network and elsewhere on the web. The reviews and comments you publish may be displayed with your member or user name. Registered members can publish reviews by logging in to their accounts; reviews submitted through our product review services cannot be deleted once uploaded. For some of our features, other members may be able to request email notifications of your new public content or publish their own comments to your reviews. You can also choose to make your wish lists private, but they are public by default. 

We may use the public content to develop aggregate ratings, personalize site views, market products or identify or feature popular members. For example, we may promote most popular or highest-earning reviews and members. While we do not expect to transfer the complete review rating and web of trust database to others (except as discussed in this policy), we use the database throughout our network and to generate results for others.

Your ECN User ID is displayed throughout the eBay Commerce Network (and so it is available to the public), and is connected to all of your ECN activity. This means that other people can see the feedback, ratings, and comments associated with your User ID. Notices sent to other community members about suspicious activity and policy violations on our sites likewise refer to specific User IDs. Therefore, if you associate your name with your User ID, the people to whom you have revealed your name will be able to personally identify your ECN activities. 

If you access our sites from a shared computer or a computer in an internet café, you must log out of your account after use, or else certain information about you such as your User ID, activity, or reminders from eBay may be visible to other individuals who use the computer after you.

### Cookies

When you access our websites or use our applications, services, or tools, we may place small data files on your computer or other device. These data files may be cookies, pixel tags, "Flash cookies," or other local storage provided by your browser or associated applications ("Cookies"). We use these data files to help us identify you as a user, customize our services, content and advertising, to measure promotional effectiveness, and to promote trust and safety. For more detailed information on our use of Cookies, see , see [Cookies and Your Privacy](http://pages.ebay.com/help/account/cookies-web-beacons.html "Cookies and Your Privacy"). 

A few important things you should know about our use of Cookies: 

  * We offer certain features that are available onlythrough the use of Cookies
  * We use both session and persistent Cookies. Session Cookies expire and no longer have any effect when you log out of your account or close your browser. Persistent Cookies remain on your device until you erase them or they expire
  * You are always free to decline Cookies if your browser permits, although doing so may interfere with your use of our websites, applications, and/or services and tools. Refer to the help section of your browser, browser extensions, or installed applications for instructions on blocking, deleting, or disabling Cookies
  * We encode and protect our Cookies so that only we can interpret the information stored in them
  * You may encounter Cookies from third parties, known as service providers, that we have allowed on our site that assist us with various aspects of our web site operations and services
  * You also may encounter Cookies from third parties on certain pages of the websites that we do not control and have not authorized. (For example, if you view a web page created by another user, there may be a cookie placed by that web page)

### Spam, Spyware, or Spoofing

eBay Inc. does not tolerate spam on the eBay Commerce Network. We do not send emails to anyone without permission, and we do not sell or rent email addresses to any unauthorized third party. This does not mean that we can prevent spam from happening on the Internet. If you believe that you have received an unsolicited email from us, please contact our Privacy Department as directed below and we will investigate.

### Accessing, Reviewing, and Changing Your Personal Information

Registered members can review and change personal information at any time by accessing the member page on their country version of Shopping.com (the [United States](http://www.shopping.com/ "United States"),the [United Kingdom](http://uk.shopping.com/ "United Kingdom"), [France](http://fr.shopping.com/ "France"), [Germany](http://de.shopping.com/ "Germany") and [Australia](http://au.shopping.com/ "Australia") ) or [Epinions](http://www.epinions.com/myaccount.html "Epinions"). You should promptly update your personal information if it changes or becomes inaccurate. You can make your ECN wish lists private by clicking "MyLists" and indicating that you want to keep your lists private. You can close your Shopping.com account by contacting Customer Support for the following country versions of Shopping.com through the following links: the [United States](http://www.shopping.com/sc/contact-us "United States"), the [United Kingdom](http://uk.shopping.com/sc/contact-us "United Kingdom"), [France](http://fr.shopping.com/sc/contact-us "France"), [Germany](http://de.shopping.com/sc/contact-us "Germany") and [Australia](http://au.shopping.com/sc/contact-us "Australia"), or your Epinions account by clicking [here](http://www.epinions.com/help/feedback_general.html "here"). We may retain some information from closed accounts so that we can comply with law, prevent fraud, assist with investigations, resolve disputes, analyze or troubleshoot programs, enforce our User Agreement, or take other actions permitted by law. Likewise if your account or membership is terminated or suspended, we may maintain some information to prevent re-registration. 

### Protection and Retention

We store and process your information on our servers located in the United States and around the world. We maintain appropriate technical, physical, and administrative security measures to protect the security of your personal information against loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure or alteration.We take steps to ensure that the personal information we collect is accurate and up to date, and delete any information that is no longer useful or relevant to our operations. 

### Third Parties

Our ECN websites may contain links to other third party websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these sites. If you have concerns about how other websites collect and use information about you, make sure to read that site's own privacy policy.

### Co-Brand Services

You'll sometimes see eBay Commerce Network content on other websites, labeled "Powered by eBay Commerce Network." For example, we syndicate our eBay Commerce Network listings for use on other companies' websites. These listings appear with another company's logo at the top of the page. When you browse these syndicated listings, you are subject to that company's privacy policy, and eBay Inc. does not collect any personal information about you or receive any personal information from these other companies. The privacy practices of our corporate family are consistent with those described in this Privacy Policy and our BCRs.

You may also interact with our product review services on websites operated by other companies. When you submit reviews or other content using our product review services, the information we collect is subject to our policies. We clearly label our product review services with the ECN Privacy Policy and User Agreement. 

### Contact Us

If your questions are not answered online, you may write to us at: eBay Inc. Attn: Legal - Global Privacy Practices, 2145 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, California 95125, or using the Contact Us form. More information about the Global Privacy Office or how to contact us is available at our [eBay Privacy Center.](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/about-us "eBay Privacy Center")
